Varadarajan Desikan

Developer

Phone 226-700-5813 E-mail pradyumdesikan@gmail.com LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/vdesikan/

As an artist with experience in multiple industries, I bring a diverse skill set to web development. My ability to meet client objectives and communicate effectively allows me to create digital designs that exceed expectations. With knowledge in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and multiple frameworks including Django, React and Node.js, I can build responsive, dynamic and intuitive web applications. My experience optimizing workflows with Python and my attention to detail and quality assurance skills ensure that projects are delivered on time and to the highest standards.

Key Transferable Skills

Attention to Detail

Creating specific characters and props requires attention to detail, which is transferable to validating code and preventing a potential security breach and ensuring successful

outcomes for the clients.

Created and optimized small add-ons with Python language (for Nuke software), which **Technical Skills**

can be transferred to working with the back end and developing APIs.

Flexibility & **Teamwork**

Experienced in handling multiple assignments with pre-set limits requires agility, the ability to prioritize and the ability to effectively work in a team environment, all transferable to working on multiple projects while working with different teams simultaneously.

Analytical & Problem-Solving Ensuring the quality of VFX packages and verifying if they match references requires analytical and problem-solving skills, which are transferable to debugging code or implementing new features.

Communication **Skills**

Constantly communicated with clients, co-workers and supervisors to meet the objectives and needs, which can be transferred to working closely with developers, analysts, and the project team to discuss requirements, design, and debugging.

Technical Skills

Web Development HTML5, CSS, JavaScript **Frameworks** Django (Python), React, Node.js

Version Control Git CI/CD Platform Gitlab

Python, JavaScript **Cloud Services Programming languages** Azure

Data Integration Talend **Software Testing** Selenium, Cucumber

Development Projects

Type of Project	Platform	Items created
Addons/Extensions	Nuke Software	Python based addons to replace, rename and organize 50+ files at a time
Clone Website	BBC	Stylesheet, Image placement, Hyperlinks
API connected	Duckduckgo	Stylesheet, Search bar function, API calling
Javascript minigame	-	Guessing the number game with looping
Javascript minigame	-	Random number generator

Experience



2023-05 Customer Service Representative

2023-06 GlassFrogBooks Inc.

- Placing orders for a drop-shipping company, making over 3500 orders in a single month individually.
- Managed multiple accounts to ensure they stayed over 95% reputation with the customers by requesting and fulfilling their feedbacks.

2022-05 Freelance Tester

Present Test.io and Ubertesters

- Conducted functional and exploratory testing on web/mobile apps for Test.io and Ubertesters.
- Collaborated with PMs/freelance testers to deliver high-quality testing results within deadlines.

2021-06 Office Coordinator/ Client Intake Coordinator

2023-03 Siva Home Health

- Managed operations, scheduling, billing, and documents for a rehab organization.
- Communicated with clients to create customized rehab plans with attention to detail.

2019-10 Customer Service Representative

2021-03 Millennium I Solutions

Worked as a CSR for multiple portfolios.

- Provided exceptional customer service by addressing inquiries and resolving issues proactively
- Managed a high volume of customer interactions daily with personalized and polite service

2018-11 Freelance Compositor

2019-01 VideoNerve Studio

Worked on the diversity-focused reality TV show, Sense Appeal.

- Utilized various editing techniques and collaborated with producers and artists to maintain a seamless production pipeline.
- Conducted client reviews to receive feedback and implement changes promptly.

2015-10 Element QC Artist/Depth Artist

2018-05 Stereo D Ltd.

Worked on over 25 movies, including Black Panther, Solo: A Star Wars Story, and Ready Player One.

- Conducted quality checks on VFX packages, verifying the accuracy and troubleshooting issues.
- Created Python addons to optimize Nuke software workflow and version control.
- Tested and optimized the addons to eliminate bugs and improve functionality.
- Converted 2D to 3D elements using keying, tracking, and compositing techniques

Education & Certifications

2023-02 Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Pearson VUE

2022-10 Test Automation Engineer and Selenium

Linkedin Learning

2022-09 Python Programming Language

Udemy

2022-06 Web Development and JavaScript

Udemy

2013-09 Visual Effects and Editing for Contemporary Media

2014-04 Fanshawe College

Graduated with a CGPA of 3.64 as one of the tops in class.

2009-06 Bachelor of Science (Visual Communication)

2012-04 DDGD Vaishnav College